<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nobelium ApS</title><link>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/</link><description>Recent content on Nobelium ApS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Steffen Otto Jensen - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 22:44:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Color Spaces</title><link>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/color-spaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 22:44:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/color-spaces/</guid><description>So Whats the deal with color spaces and profiles on JPEG images. Without going too deep I will explain how, and what to do.
For these examples I will be using Pixelmator Pro, but everything say will hold equally true in Photoshop, Gimp or any other image editing software.
First a short description of what color spaces are. A color space defines which colors are available. Some color spaces are very large, and others are more limited.</description></item><item><title>Excel Vlookup</title><link>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/excel-vlookup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 10:50:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/excel-vlookup/</guid><description>Excel vlookup is super usefull, but I can never remember how to use it. So it&amp;rsquo;s always a struggle, and wastes a lot of time.
So we have a small table with parts, on a sheet named &amp;ldquo;primary: Note that the last &amp;ldquo;Exists&amp;rdquo; column is empty, we wish to populate this from another sheet.
Now we have another table, on a sheet named &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo;: So we want to make a star in the exists column of the first table, if that partnumber is present in table two.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/static/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 01:19:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/static/about/</guid><description>Who am I? And why did i create a blog?.And why should you read what I write here? And what is Nobelium ApS?
Let&amp;rsquo;s take one at a time.
My name is Steffen, and I live in Grenå on Djursland (In Denmark). Together with my wife and daughter. I&amp;rsquo;ve made this blog to have a place to write down my thoughts. I&amp;rsquo;m very reserved towards modern social media, but very open to technology.</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on DPI / PPI</title><link>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/perspectives-on-dpi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:50:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.nobelium-aps.dk/en/blog/perspectives-on-dpi/</guid><description>Monitors / Displays Often DPI is advertized on products you buy. Such as monitors, phones, printers, scanners and inside software. It&amp;rsquo;s actually not so complicated to understand what it is in general. But it can be a little opaque sometimes especially when you talk printing, and image files. Then it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get a little confused. Actually DPI should be used when talking about prints, and PPI (Pixels Per Inch) should be used for displays.</description></item></channel></rss>